AKI GAO

(703) 901-0568 | aki.gao@user1st.com | iknowht.ml | github.com/iknowhtml

Profile

I am a Software Engineer with a passion for technology and creating software that positively impact people and society. My areas of professional interests include the web, distributed systems and understanding the practices & habits of productive engineers, teams and organizations. I offer over three years of professional experience in software development using the JavaScript ecosystem and functional programming paradigms in Agile environments, including over one year of professional experience in web & mobile accessibility and remote work experience across international time zones.

Work Experience

User1st - Software Engineer, Remote

February 2021 - Present

- Implement new features and resolve bugs for Check1st, an automated web accessibility assessment SaaS platform.
- Coordinate directly with enterprise stakeholders to analyze requirements and communicate product features requests and issues to product owner.
- Lead instruction for developer oriented accessibility training with 20+ hours of instruction time covering a range of topics including accessibility standards & principles (e.g., WCAG 2.1, POUR), assistive technologies (e.g., NVDA) and best practices for developing and testing accessible software.
- Provide technical support to enterprise customers, including a major wireless network operator and a domestic passenger rail road service, as well as engineering support to sales.

User1st - Solutions Integrator, Washington, D.C./Remote

January 2020 - February 2021

- Remediated websites to comply with accessibility standards using User1st's uRemediate™ platform for 20+ clients, including a major wireless network operator and a Fortune 500 healthcare provider.
- Audited client websites and mobile applications for compliance with the WCAG 2.1 AA standard and Section 508 quidelines.
- Created internal tooling to automate tasks & improve productivity including:
 - A command-line tool built with Node.js & Puppeteer to automate website URL discovery and autogenerate web page screenshots to reduce time estimations by 33% and improve accuracy by 50% for client websites.
 - A cross-browser extension built with the WebExtension browser API to inject runtime environment for client sites without the neccessary uRemediate™ snippet installed to replace unreliable tooling in 95% of use cases.

Alluminate - Full Stack Developer (Freelance), Washington, D.C.

November 2017 - June 2018

- Designed and developed the company's homepage, as well as landing pages and a user portal for several products.
- Audited and tested Ethereum smart contracts for ERC-721 compatibility & general correctness, as well as bootstrapped metamask integration for front end clients and Ethereum test net infrastructure for smart contract deployments.

Skills

Languages:

JavaScript, TypeScript, Shell (Bash)

Front End & Accessibility Technologies: Figma, HTML, CSS, React, JAWS, NVDA, VoiceOver (iOS), TalkBack (Android), ARIA Development and Testing Tools: Git, NPM, Yarn, Webpack, Babel, Jest, ESlint Back End & Infrastructure Technologies: Nodejs, Express, PostgreSQL, CircleCI, Docker,

Kubernetes

Education

The University of Virginia: School of Engineering and Applied Science (SEAS)

August 2016

• B.S. Computer Engineering & B.S. Electrical Engineering